Hello everyone, how are you all? I am
Amit Raj Sharma, your personal advisor, and you are
watching UD Real. The title of today's video is
Mishri or Majumdar ji.
He wants to understand the Aditya Birla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited
plan in detail
with examples. So, please check out the Life Insurance playlist on the channel,
you will find the video.
Majumdar ji, thank you very much for your comment.
For your convenience, the link to the Life Insurance playlist has
already been given in the description of the video. So, do
not forget to like the video, share it, and
tell us in the comment section if
you want the next video on this topic. Let's start today's
video and learn about the retail
Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company
Limited's Akshay Plan. If this
planning life insurance is not done, it is
market related, which will not be
on us. Every year
at the end of the financial year, it will announce the bonus rate, which will give us
returns and
our life cover will remain during the policy term, that is, if there is a
death, then the nominee will definitely get the
benefit. How will
all the benefits be received in the plan, let's move forward.  You will understand,
but before that let me tell you that there are two variants in this plan,
you can take only one of them,
first is long term income and second is whole
life income, both are different from each other,
now we do not want any confusion, so for
this reason in today's video we are
talking only about the long term income option, so let us know the
eligibility criteria of the long term income option, the
limit of space is from 30 days to
55 years, for minors, if you
choose the long term income option and
take the plan, then there will be no benefit table until I become an adult, so for
this reason the
minimum limit for maturity ahead is automatically 18 years
and the maximum limit for maturity ahead is 84 years, the
option for premium payment term is from 6 years to 15 years, it was a
small forgiveness, the
option for monthly right policy term is 25 years,
30 years, 35 years and 40 years, the minimum
premium is  The limit is Rs 24000
and the minimum shot limit is Rs
1445060. Now we will talk about the
benefit here, so the first benefit is
bonus. There are two options in bonus, cash bonus
and accumulate, that is, instead of taking it in installments, you keep
collecting the bonus hand in hand,
which you can withdraw later if needed, or
on maturity
or on death or surrender. You will get it all at once,
but if you choose the cash bonus option, then
you will start getting this cash bonus from the end of the first year of the policy. Till
when will you get it, till majority or
till surrender. The calculation of bonus is done on the
basis of interest only. You
can take the bonus annually, half yearly,
quarterly and even monthly
if you choose the cash bonus option.
Now see, because of the cash bonus option, the
income earned in the term plan option is
justified. Here, if you want to collect the bonus, then
a normal endowment policy  It keeps
accumulating in me also, right, okay,
now when it comes to majority benefit,
what will you get on maturity, understand and you will get it.
If you have taken the bonus in the form of cash bonus, if you have
chosen the cash bonus option, then you will get the last installment
of cash bonus. If it has
accumulated, then you will get the accumulated
bonus plus terminal bonus
if the company has announced it. So when it comes to
majority benefit, you will get all the major benefits on date. You will get the
last installment of cash bonus.
If you are taking the bonus in installments,
if you are accumulating, then
you will get that accumulated bonus plus terminal
bonus. Now who will get this?
Your nominee will get this benefit, you know this thing.
Okay, now let us take an
example here so that we can understand. Let us take
Mr. C, whose age is 30
years, wants to take a regular income plan. In such a situation,
he took Aditya Birla Sun Life's
Akshay Long Term Income Option.
Premium payment of 30 years here is 10 years
and the bonus here, he chose the cash bonus
option and wanted  They should get their annual cash bonus
in installments. The rate of bonus
in this type of plans
of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company ranges from ₹35 to
₹45 on a sum of ₹1000.
Now the annual premium that they
are paying here is ₹70000.
Right now the factor here depends on the premium rate.
The information about premium rate is displayed on our screen.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6 are the premium rates.
Based on these only, the support factor is here
which is multiplied with the analyzed premium,
which is now our premium value.
Because in Bantu, the
premium is kept from ₹50000 to ₹999. So
in such a situation, the sum factor will be
1095.4%. So for ₹70000, we will get ₹
100095.44 here, so
our total here will be Rs.7668. Let's do it.  The
rate of bonus is ₹35
on a sum of ₹1000, that is,
3.25% of the sum. Why are we doing this?
Because this plan is new, so its
bonus rate will be known in the next financial year. We
cannot know it now.
Therefore, we are resuming
this type of plan on the basis of the performance of the bonus rate of their company.
I have given the link
in the description from there, you will be able to see and understand why
we considered such a rate.
Only on the other side, the bonus will be
2683828 paise. Now,
how much cashback would you have received before maturity? You would have received
78310 because
we multiplied 26838.8 by 29. Now when it comes to
maturity benefit, understand the
short amount,
7668 and the last installment
of cash bonus will be 26838. If we add these, then the
benefit will be 85148 paise plus terminal bonus.  You must have
received 78310 paise. Now we will talk about the
death of Mr. C. It is
happening after 12 years of the policy. So first of all,
what does Samashwar Dan Death say?
11 times the annual
premium is 17000. If we multiply it by 11, it becomes 770
thousand. Now we have to compare it.
105% of the total paid premium gives
₹70000 as annual premium. If we multiply it by
7 lakh rupees in 10 years, then it will become 735000 five percent of
7 lakh rupees. Now
we will compare it with the total amount.
What is our total amount?
7668. If we compare all three, then the
amount of 770 thousand will be more. So the total
amount will be ours here. 770 thousand
rupees. And the installment of cash bonus will be of
26838 paise. Now what does our pain say?
Plus the last installment of cash bonus plus
our terminal bonus.  On the basis of example,
okay, so our
bonus here is 70000 plus 26838 paise, if we
add these then we will get
796838 paise here plus
terminal bonus, terminal bonus announced by the company.
Now when it comes to
loan, you can take loan up to C percent of the surrender value. The
rate of interest of the loan is
not fixed, it keeps
changing, it is 8.5% which is
always mentioned in the policy document. Now when it comes to
guaranteed surrender value, this plan can be surrendered
only after paying premium continuously for at least 2 years
and
in such a case, the guaranteed cylinder value will be
multiplied by the guaranteed surrender value factor
in the total paid analysis premium and from that the amount of cash bonus will be deducted.
If you have taken it in installments then
okay, now let us
take an example here, suppose
Mr. C is going to surrender the policy after the premium payment
term,
so in such a situation, whatever we have done in 10 years  The total paid
premium will be 700000 and we must have
received it in the form of ₹70000, what will we do with it, if we
multiply 26838 paise by 10 then the amount will become 2
lakh
68382 paise, the guaranteed
cylinder value factor here will be 55%
which will be applied, from where did we get the
guaranteed under value factor and that is the thing, it was
taken from the surrender value chart which we have
already shared on the Telegram channel,
10 years are completed in positive of 30 years,
then our
guaranteed surrender value factor of 55% has come out here,
for your convenience
we have also given the link of the Telegram channel in the description,
so 7 lakh less will be calculated here by 55% and from that the
total bonus which has been received of
₹268382 paise, if we subtract it from this then
55% of 7 lakh will come out to be 385000, from
this we will subtract 2 68382
1016617 The amount will be 20 paise The
revival period in the plan is 5 years, which means
if you
stop paying the premium on the policy, then you can revive it in the next year
Now in the next section we will understand the whole life
income option and
what are the benefits of the paid up policy because the
surrender calculation will be done in this way The
loan amount is also from
both, yes, there are some basic
features which will be explained in the important section
Rest you can tell in the comment section if you have something to
say, if you want to give feedback, if you have
any suggestion, please do tell If you want a
video to be made especially according to your comment, then definitely ask your question
Thank you very much for watching the video till the end Understand one thing yourself and
explain to others also that insurance is a
protection and protection is never
taken incompletely and please make it a
habit to read the policy document, hence we are providing
PDF on Telegram channel